Finding Aid for University Musical Society (University of Michigan) Publications, 1874-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
University Musical Society (University of Michigan) publications 1874-2010
University of Michigan. University Musical Society.
1 oversize folders
13 linear feet
0362, Bimu, N1 2
Private society affiliated with the University of Michigan, sponsors music, opera, theatrical and other performances. Contains brochures or pamphlets, flyers and other publicity publications. The two volume history One Hundred Years of Great Performances, 1879-1979 is included in addition to the newsletter UMS Notes. Also contains programs of various performances sponsored by the University Musical Society.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Material from the University Musical Society (donor 2996 ) was first received in 1953.
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The publications are open for research.
[See the history in the finding aid for University Musical Society (University of Michigan) Records.]
The UMS Publications, 1874-2010 (13 linear feet) were received from the University Musical Society staff in periodic transfers. Additional publications, collected by the Graduate Library, have been interfiled to fill gaps in the series. Publications is composed of two series: Unit Publications and Sub-Unit Publications.
The Unit Publications series contains printed material published specifically by the University Musical Society. These publications are defined as being widely distributed and may be published at regular intervals. They are arranged by genre of the publication.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Choral Union.; University of Michigan--Choral organizations.; University of Michigan. School of Music.; Ann Arbor May Festival.; University of Michigan. Choral Union.; University of Michigan. School of Music.; Ann Arbor May Festival.; University of Michigan. University Musical Society.
Genre Terms:
Annual reports.; Pamphlets.; Histories.; Newsletters.; Posters.; Programs.
- Unit Publications
  The Unit Publications series (12 linear feet) contains six file: annual reports, brochures, histories, newsletters, programs, and scripts. Brochures, flyers, and publicity items will be found under the heading "Brochures." The four additional file are "Histories," "Newsletters," "Programs," and "Scripts."
  The annual reports cover the period from 1939 through 1958. The file "Brochures" includes promotional material of many sorts, most of it created by the UMS. A few promotional items created by the artists and used by UMS are included. Under "Histories", the researcher will find a copy of One Hundred Years of Great Performances, a publication celebrating the centennial of the University Musical Society. It is found in Box 12. Within the Publications the most important file is the complete set of Programs for University Musical Society presentations from 1874 through to the present. Programs contain information on artists, photographs, publicity and reviews.
  The comprehensive file of house Programs begins in 1874. From 1874 to 1879 programs are included for concerts given under the auspices of the University of Michigan including "Grand Commencement Concerts." On December 16, 1879, the "First Concert of the Ann Arbor Choral Union" was given. The name "University Musical Society" appears on a notice for the "First Public Rehearsal given by the University Musical Society and the Choral Union," May 4, 1880. The original concert series sponsored by the University Musical Society was called the Choral Union Series; its first season was 1879/1880. In 1894 the first of the May Festivals was held. In some years special concerts were held and in 1919/20 the Extra Concert Series and the Matinee Musicale Series began. The Matinee Musicale Series ran for two years, the Extra Concert Series continued through 1927/28. During 1892/93 the University School of Music sponsored a chamber series in Newberry Hall. Programs for that series are included.
  In 1940 the UMS began a pre-Christmas presentation of the Messiah. In 1941 a Chamber Music Festival was initiated and a Special Concert was added. The Extra Concert Series was brought back beginning in 1946/47. By 1963/64 the presentation lineup included: a pre-season concert, ten Choral Union Series concerts, five concerts in the Extra Concerts series, a Chamber Arts Series of seven concerts, a three-concert Chamber Dance Festival, a special presentation by the New York City Opera, two Messiah performances, three concerts in the Chamber Music Festival, six concerts in the May Festival, and four concerts in a new Summer Concert Series, a total of 42 performances. In 1971 the Choice Series began. The 1973/74 season included 57 concerts in eight series. Beginning in 1984/85 programs for the Ann Arbor Summer Festival are included. Also included are the program for the dedication of the Frieze organ, December 14, 1894, and miscellaneous organ and other recitals.
  - Annual Reports 1939/40-1957/58 (Box 1)
  - Histories
    - Fifty Years and Counting: Chamber Concerts Presented by the University Musical Society in Rackham Auditorium, 1941-1991, 1991 (Box 1)
    - One Hundred Years of Great Performances, 1879-1979, 2 volumes
      - Vol. 1 1879 -- 1979, 1980 (Box 1)
      - Vol. 2 Repertoire Volume, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Newsletter
    - UMS Notes
      - 1989-2002 incomplete run, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Brochures, flyers, publicity items
    - Undated (Box 1)
    - 1880/81-1889/90 (Box 1)
    - 1890/91-1899/1900 (Box 1)
    - 1900/01-1909/10 (Box 1)
    - 1910/11-1919/20 (Box 1)
    - 1920/21-1929/30 (Box 1)
    - 1930/31-1939/40 (Box 1)
    - 1940/41-1949/50 (Box 1)
    - 1950/51-1959/60 (Box 1)
    - 1960/61-1969/70 (Box 1)
    - 1970/71-1973/74 (Box 1)
    - 1974/75-1978/79 (Box 1)
    - 1979/80-1982/83 (Box 1)
    - 1983/84-1985/86 (Box 1)
    - 1986/87-1988/89 (Box 1)
    - 1989/90 (Box 2)
    - 1990/91 (Box 2)
    - 1991/92 (Box 2)
    - 1992/93 (Box 2)
    - 1993/94 (Box 2)
    - 1994/95 (Box 2)
    - 1995/96 (Box 2)
    - 1996/97 (Box 2)
    - 1997/98 (Box 2)
    - 1998/99 (Box 2)
    - 1999/00 (Box 2)
    - 2000/01 (Box 2)
    - 2001/02 (Box 12)
    - 2002/03 (Box 12)
    - 2003/04 (Box 12)
    - 2004/05 (Box 12)
    - 2005/06 (Box 12)
    - 2006/07 (Box 12)
    - 2007/08 (Box 12)
    - 2008/09 (Box 13)
    - 2009/10 (Box 13)
  - Programs, unbound
    - 1874-1879 (Box 3)
    - 1879-1883/84 (Box 3)
    - 1884/85-1888/89 (Box 3)
    - 1889/90-1893/94 (Box 3)
    - 1894/95-1898/99 (Box 3)
    - 1899/00-1900/01 (Box 3)
    - 1901/02-1902/03 (Box 3)
    - 1903/04-1904/05 (Box 3)
    - 1905/06-1906/07 (Box 3)
    - 1907/08-1908/09 (Box 3)
    - 1909/10-1910/11 (Box 3)
    - 1911/12-1912/13 (Box 3)
    - 1913/14-1914/15 (Box 3)
    - 1915/16-1916/17 (Box 3)
    - 1917/18-1918/19 (Box 3)
    - 1919/20-1920/21 (Box 3)
    - 1921/22-1922/23 (Box 3)
    - 1923/24-1924/25 (Box 3)
    - 1925/26-1926/27 (Box 4)
    - 1927/28-1928/29 (Box 4)
    - 1929/30-1930/31 (Box 4)
    - 1931/32-1932/33 (Box 4)
    - 1933/34-1934/35 (Box 4)
    - 1935/36-1936/37 (Box 4)
    - 1937/38-1938/39 (Box 4)
    - 1939/40-1940/41 (Box 4)
    - 1941/42-1942/43 (Box 4)
    - 1943/44-1944/45 (Box 4)
    - 1945/46-1946/47 (Box 4)
    - 1947/48-1948/49 (Box 4)
    - 1949/50-1950/51 (Box 5)
    - 1951/52-1952/53 (Box 5)
    - 1953/54-1954/55 (Box 5)
    - 1955/56-1956/57 (Box 5)
    - 1957/58-1958/59 (Box 5)
    - 1959/60-1960/61 (Box 5)
    - 1961/62-1962/63 (Box 5)
    - 1963/64-1964/65 (Box 5)
    - 1965/66-1966/67 (Box 5)
    - 1967/68-1968/69 (Box 5)
    - 1969/70-1970/71 (Box 5)
    - 1971/72-1972/73 (Box 6)
    - 1973/74-1974/75 (Box 6)
    - 1975/76-1976/77 (Box 6)
    - 1977/78-1978/79 (Box 6)
    - 1979/80-1980/81 (Box 6)
    - 1981/82-1982/83 (Box 6)
    - 1983/84-1984/85 (Box 6)
    - 1985/86-1986/87 (Box 6)
    - 1987/88-1988/89 (Box 6)
    - 1989/90 (Box 7)
    - 1990/91 (Box 7)
    - 1991/92 (Box 7)
    - 1993/94 (Box 7)
    - 1994/95 (Box 7)
    - 1995/96 (Box 7)
    - 1996/97 (Box 7)
    - 1997/98 (Box 8)
    - 1998/99, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - 1999/00, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - 2000/01, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - 2002/03, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - 2003/04, 3 folders (Box 8)
      (includes program and special publications commemorating the re-opening weekend of Hill Auditorium)
    - Fall 2004 (with inserts) (Box 9)
    - Winter 2005 (Box 9)
    - 2005/06 (Box 9)
    - 2006/07 (Box 9)
    - Fall 2007 (Box 9)
    - Winter 2008 (Box 9)
    - Fall 2008 (Box 9)
    - 2008/09 (Box 9)
    - Winter 2009 (Box 9)
    - Fall 2009 (Box 9)
    - Winter 2010 (Box 9)
- Sub-Unit Publications
  The Sub-Unit Publications series contains publications from subordinate offices, departments, programs, laboratories and organizations within the University Musical Society. These publications are arranged alphabetically by the creating sub-unit.
  The Sub-Unit Publications series (2 linear feet) includes material published by units within the society. These include the Development Department, the Education and Audience Development Department, and the Youth Education Program.
  The Education and Audience Development Department document their activities in calendar of program activities, covering the period 1996 through 1998. This department also created several Teacher Resource Guides. The Youth Education Program also designed Teacher Resource Guides from 1998 to the present.
  - Development Department 1998
    - Newsletters
      - Cookbook News, 1998 (Box 10)
  - Education and Audience Development Department
    - Annual Reports 2000/01 (Box 10)
    - Brochures, 1996/1997-2005/06 (Box 10)
    - Calendars, including photographic documentation of program activities 1996-1998, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Newsletters 1997/98 (Box 10)
    - Study Guides 2001-2003, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Teacher Resource Guides 1995-1997, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Youth Education Program
    - Brochures, 2000- (Box 10)
    - Teacher Resource Guides
      - 1998-1999 (Box 10)
      - 1999-2000, 4 folders (Box 10)
      - 2001-2002, 7 folders (Box 10)
      - 2002-2003, 4 folders (Box 10)
      - 2003-2004, 8 folders (Box 11)
      - 2004 (Box 11)
      - 2004-2005 (Box 11)
      - 2005, 3 folders (Box 11)
      - 2005-2006 (Box 11)
      - 2008-2009, 2 folders (Box 11)
      - 2009-2010, 2 folders (Box 11)
- Miscellaneous Outsize Material
  - Festival Journal, "1st Annual Music Festival," May 18, 19 1894 published by the University Musical Society. (Folder 1)
    (located at Fimu N3)
  - University Musical Society 1986/1987 Calendar (Folder 1)
  - "Concert Makers" Program announcement for 1991-1992 (Folder 1)
  - Posters 2001-2002, 2004, 2008-2010, undated (Folder 1)